Encounters are mysterious! But the world is even more so!
لقاءات البشر مغلّفة بالغموض، والعالم تلفّه طبقات أكثر حتّى
I'm so glad I'm with you!
!أنا مسرورٌ حقّاً لكوني معك
Today's all deduction! Let's change our view of people sometimes!
!اليوم استنتاجات بالكامل! لنغيّر نظرتنا للطرف الآخر أحياناً
He sees the single truth for what it is,
يرى الحقيقة الواحدة
and looks like a kid but has the mind of an adult!
يحمل مظهر طفل، لكنّ عقله عقل بالغ
His name? Detective Conan!
!اسمه المتحرّي كونان
Thanks to Ran's plan to bring her parents back together,
بعد خطّة ران في إعادة أبيها وأمّها ،لبعضهما بشكلٍ ما
we came to a midsummer beach.
أتينا لشاطئ في منتصف الصيف
But a girl we met fell into critical condition after a sea snake bit her.
لكن دخلت فتاة جامعية تعرّفنا عليها هناك في حالة حرجة بعد أن عضّتها أفعى بحر
This was no accident! It's a criminal act disguised as an accident!
!لم تكن حادثة، بل جريمة بقناع حادث
Queen Hotel, Izu
فندق الملكة، إيزو
What? Bring her insurance card to the hospital right away?
ماذا؟ بطاقة تأمينها؟
The hospital staff says it'd be best to have it,
قال العاملون في المشفى أنّ من الأفضل امتلاكها
plus I feel all alone...
وأنا لا أشعر بارتياح لوحدي
Kiwako always takes it when traveling, so it should be somewhere.
،تجلبها كيواكو معها عند السفر دوماً فلا بدّ أنّها موجودة في مكان
But never mind that! How is she?!
!اترك ذلك جانباً، كيف حالها؟
She's still in the Intensive Care Unit.
دخلت غرفة العناية المركّزة، ولم تخرج بعد
I think her condition's gotten worse.
يبدو أنّ حالتها تدهورت
The doctors keep rushing in and out, but they won't tell me anything.
،الأطباء يدخلون ويخرجون باستمرار لكن لا أحد يخبرني بشيء
Do you think she might die?
هل ستموت يا ترى؟
You idiot! What kind of crap is that?!
!يا أحمق! ما الذي تهذي به؟
I'll get her insurance card and be right there! Just wait quietly!
!سأجلب بطاقة تأمينها وآتي فوراً، فلتنتظرني فقط
You and Kiwako are in the same room, right?
أظنّ أنّك كنتِ في نفس الغرفة مع كيواكو، أليس كذلك؟
Yeah.
بـ-بلى
Oh no! The card key is still in the room!
كلا، ما زالت بطاقة المفتاح في الغرفة
I forgot it when she asked me to get a bath towel from our room.
نسيتها عندما طلبت منّي كيواكو الذهاب لجلب منشفة استحمام
What do we do?
ما العمل؟
It locks automatically, so we can't get inside.
تُقفل آلياً، فلا نستطيع الدخول
Sheesh.
ليس باليد حيلة
I'll call the front desk from our room and have 'em bring a spare key.
سأتّصل بمكتب الاستقبال من غرفتنا وأطلب منهم جلب مفتاح بديل
Yes, that's right. Room 406. Yes. Yes.
.أجل، صحيح، الغرفة 406 أجل، أجل
Thanks. Sorry for the bother.
شكراً، نعتذر على الإزعاج
Hey!
أخبرني
W-What is it, kid? Don't scare me like that.
ما-ما الأمر يا فتى؟ لا تفزعني هكذا
You all went scuba diving around noon, right?
ذهبتم جميعاً لغوص السكوبا عند الظهيرة، أليس كذلك؟
Yeah.
بلى
Did you catch anything?
هل اصطدتم شيئاً؟
Like fish.
مثل السمك
No, I didn't get anything this time.
كلا، لم أصطد شيئاً هذه المرّة
What about the others?
والبقيّة كذلك؟
I dunno.
لا أدري
We're familiar with these waters, and we all did our own thing,
جميعنا معتادون على بحر هذه المنطقة، وغصنا بمفردنا
so I'm not sure who did what.
فلا أعرف ما الذي فعله الآخرون بالضبط
I think Masahiko and Kiwako-chan wore matching wetsuits
أظنّ ماساهيكو وكيواكو-تشان ارتديا بذلتَي غوص متماثلتين مع ذلك
and did their diving at the same spot, though.
وغاصا في المكان نفسه
They're really close!
إنّهما مقرّبان كثيراً
Yeah. Them and Hiroshi are all childhood friends.
أجل، فهما بالإضافة إلى هيروشي أصدقاء طفولة
They've always had fun together, since they were kids.
يبدو أنّهم كانوا يمرحون سوياً في صغرهم دوماً
They're all classmates?
كلّهم زملاء دراسة؟
No, Hiroshi and Masahiko are the same age as me,
كلا، هيروشي وماساهيكو في نفس عمري
but Kiwako-chan is one year younger, the same age as Harumi-chan.
،لكنّ كيواكو-تشان أصغر بعام مثل سنّ هارومي-تشان
To be honest, I planned to quit this club my second year of college.
بصراحة، كنت أنوي ترك هذا النادي في سنتي الثانية في الجامعة
But I changed my mind when Kiwako-chan's group joined.
لكنّي غيّرت رأيي عندما انضمّت مجموعة كيواكو-تشان
I guess it was love at first sight.
لعلّه كان حُبّاً من النظرة الأولى
Huh?!
ماذا؟
How stupid! Why am I telling all this to a kid?
يا للحماقة، ما الذي أخبر هذا الصبيّ به؟
Wait a minute!
انتظر
Does that mean--?
...أيعني هذا أنّه
That person and that person... Could it be?!
أهما... أيمكن؟
There you are.
تفضّلوا
Thank you.
شكراً لك
Let's see...
...حسناً
Insurance card, insurance card...
...بطاقة التأمين، بطاقة التأمين
Geez! Here's where you left it!
يا إلهي، لا أمل منك
I assume this is your card key?
هذه بطاقة مفتاحك، أليس كذلك؟
Yeah.
بلى
Can you help me? I can't find Kiwako's insurance card.
أيمكنك مساعدتي؟ لا أجد بطاقة تأمين كيواكو
Did she maybe forget it?
لعلّها نسيتها وحسب
Inside the towel at the bottom of the bag.
إنّها داخل المنشفة في أسفل الحقيبة
Just look.
ابحثي فحسب
The towel at the bottom of the bag...
...المنشفة في أسفل الحقيبة
H-Here it is! How did you know?!
ها-ها هي! كيف عرفت؟
My grandmother taught it to me when I was a kid, and I taught them.
علّمتني جدّتي هذا في صغري، وعلّمتهما
That's childhood friends for ya!
!كما يُتوقع من أصدقاء الطفولة
I'm not the only one. Masahiko knows it, too.
لستُ الوحيد، يعرف ماساهيكو الأمر أيضاً
Say, Detective. You have a car, right?
اسمع أيّها المتحرّي، لديك سيارة، أليس كذلك؟
Yeah. It's a rental.
أجل، إنّها مُستأجرة
Then could you drive us three to the hospital?
هلّا أخذتنا نحن الثلاثة إلى المشفى إذاً؟
Yeah, no problem.
نعم، لا أمانع
Then let me come, too!
!دعني أرافقكم إذاً
I'm worried about Kiwako-san...
...فأنا أشعر بالقلق على كيواكو-سان
Don't be stupid. Five people can't fit in that tiny car.
حمقاء، لن يتّسع خمسة أشخاص في تلك السيّارة الصغيرة
It's all right.
لا بأس
I can drop her off at the hospital.
لا بأس، سآخذ ران بسيّارتي
What are those suitcases for, Mom?!
لمَ جلبتِ أمتعتك يا أمّي؟
Oh, you can't tell? As soon as I drop you off, I'm going home.
ماذا؟ ألم تستنتجي؟ سأرجع للمنزل بعدما أنزلك
Wait, Mom!
!مهلك يا أمّي
I don't want to share the same space with this lunkhead anymore.
لا أريد التواجد في نفس الحيّز مع هذا البليد بعد الآن
Hey, Eri.
اسمعي يا إيري
What?
ماذا؟
We need to talk later.
أريد الكلام معك لاحقاً
Oh? What about? I can't wait to find out.
ماذا؟ عن ماذا يا ترى؟ أتطلّع للمعرفة
Come on!
!مهلكما
You're going too fast, Mom!
!أنتِ تسرعين كثيراً يا أمّي
Sheesh. You don't have to sulk because he didn't notice your ring.
يا إلهي، لا داعي لتستائي هكذا لأنّه لم يلحظ خاتمك فحسب
It's not the ring. It's the incident.
ليس الخاتم، بل الحادثة
The incident?
الحادثة؟
Not everything adds up yet, but this is clearly a murder case.
هناك أجزاء ناقصة، لكنّ هذه جريمة قتل بكلّ وضوح
Murder?!
جريمة قتل؟
And I'm angry at him for not even realizing it!
وأنا غاضبةٌ منه لأنّه لم يدرك الأمر
Yes. It's a murder case, and I have an idea who's responsible.
،صحيح... إنّها جريمة قتل ولديّ فكرة عن هويّة الفاعل
There's just one thing I don't understand...
هنالك نقطة واحدة فحسب لا أفهمها
Why did that person do that then?
لمَ قام ذاك الشخص بذاك الشيء آنذاك؟
What could it be?
ما قد يكون يا ترى؟
Do you mean the incident?
تقصدين الحادثة؟
No, what he wants to tell me.
كلا، ما يريد إخباري به
He said we have to talk later.
فقد قال أنّه يريد الكلام معي لاحقاً
Divorce... Custody rights... Or perhaps...
...الطلاق... حقّ وصايتك... أم
Mom...
أمّي؟
It's probably nothing at all. He's only testing me.
لعلّ لا شيء هناك وحسب، إنّه يختبرني فقط
Testing?!
!يختبر؟
It's always the same.
الأمر هكذا دوماً
He gets me worked up and then watches me squirm.
يجعلني أنفعل، ثم يراقب ارتباكي
He's so self-conceited!
يا لغطرسته
Now I see! So that's what the deal is!
فهمت، هكذا الأمر إذاً
Ran. Sorry, but I can't stand it anymore.
ران، أنا آسفة... لكن يبدو أنّي لم أعد أحتمل
Mom!
أمّي
No question about it! That person is behind this!
!لا شكّ في الأمر، الفاعل... هو ذاك الشخص
West Izu Hospital
مشفى إيزو الغربيّ
Masahiko! I brought it!
!ماساهيكو! جلبتها معي
Kiwako's insurance card!
!بطاقة تأمين كيواكو
Everyone!
رفاق
So, how's her condition?!
إذاً، كيف حالها؟
How is she, Brother?
كيف هي يا أخي؟
I don't know. She's still in the ICU.
لا أدري، لا تزال في غرفة العناية المركّزة
Let me know when you find out how she is.
أخبريني عن حالها بعدما تعرفين
You're leaving, Mom?! But Dad said he has to talk with you!
ستغادرين يا أمّي؟ لكن ألم يخبرك أبي أنّه يريد الكلام معك؟
Talk? Do I really need to lend my ear to that lady-killer?
الكلام؟ أتظنّين أنّي بحاجة للاستماع لحديث زير النساء هذا؟
Oh, really?! You're fans of mine?
حقّاً ذلك؟ أنتنّ معجبات لي؟
Dad!
!أبي
What a lost cause. Maybe I should give the guy a hand.
لا أمل منه، ربما عليّ مساعدته
Say, Nurse.
حضرة الممرضة
Yes?
أجل؟
I have a favor to ask.
لديّ طلب صغير
Wait, Mom! He can't help it! He's famous!
!انتظري يا أمّي! ليس الأمر بيده، فأبي مشهور
He's all smiles at a time like this! I've had enough of his callousness!
سئمت من برودة ذلك الرجل الذي يتبسّم في أوقات كهذه
But that's because--
...لكنّ ذلك بسبب
Paging Kisaki Eri and Matsuzaki Harumi from the Queen Hotel.
،نداء لـ كيساكي إيري-ساما المقيمة في فندق الملكة ولـ ماتسوزاكي هاروما-ساما المقيم في الفندق نفسه
Please come to the hospital director's office immediately.
تعالا لمكتب مدير المشفى من فضلكما
Mori Kogoro is waiting.
موري كوغورو-ساما بانتظاركما
Alright!
!حسنٌ
Me?
أنا؟
Mori-san!
!موري-سان
Wait! Little boy!
!يا ولد
I'm sorry! I'll bring it right back!
!آسف! سأرجعه سريعاً
Director
مكتب المدير
Why did you call us here like that?!
!ما الذي تنويه باستدعائي هكذا؟
If you have something to tell me, just say it already!
!إذا لديك ما تخبرني به، فانطق فوراً
Mom...
...أمّي
Yikes...
!مخيفة
Umm, I can come back later if I'm in the way.
المعذرة، يمكنني العودة لاحقاً إذا كنت أضايقكما
I'm concerned about Kiwako, too.
أنا قلقة على كيواكو أيضاً
So you are concerned about her?
أنتِ قلقة عليها بالفعل إذاً؟
Can't say I blame you.
لا عجب
After all, the difference between murder and attempted murder hangs in the balance.
،فالميزان يتأرجح بين كونها جريمة قتل ومحاولة الإقدام على جريمة قتل
Yes. That wasn't an accident.
أجل، لم تكن حادثة
It was a premeditated act meant to kill.
كانت جريمةً بسابق الإصرار والترصّد للقتل
Someone purposely had the sea snake bite Kiwako-san.
تعرّضت كيواكو-سان للعضّ المتعمّد من الأفعى التي كان يحملها الفاعل
Matsuzaki Harumi-san... that someone was you!
!ماتسوزاكي هارومي-سان... كانت أنت
You can't be serious!
!لا يمكن
The fang marks.
آثار الأنياب
Fang marks?
آثار الأنياب؟
Sea snakes have rather small heads.
رؤوس أفاعي البحر صغيرة
If one bit a human, it'd be somewhere small, like a fingertip.
إذا عضّت بشرياً، فستكون منطقة صغيرة مثل أطراف الأصابع
Yet, Kiwako-san's fang marks were on the back of her hand,
مع ذلك، آثار الأنياب على كيواكو-سان كانت على كفّها
where a sea snake couldn't have bitten her.
حيث لا تستطيع أفعى البحر عضّها هناك
When rushing to help, she held the head of the snake she had hidden,
عندما هرعت لنجدة كيواكو-سان، أمسكت برأس أفعى البحر التي كانت تخفيها
forced its mouth open, and had it bite down as if it had attacked.
أجبرتها على فتح فمها، وجعلتها تعضّها كما لو أنّها قامت بمهاجمتها
Isn't that right, Harumi-san?!
ألستُ محقّاً يا هارومي-سان؟
I see. You pretended to play dumb but actually saw through it all.
فهمت، تظاهرت بالسذاجة، لكنّك كشفت ما حصل
Then tell us this, Great Detective.
فلتخبرنا حضرة المتحرّي إذاً
How can you be sure it was Harumi-san?
ما هو أساس ادّعائك بأنّها الفاعلة؟
Couldn't any of the others have done it too?
ألم يكن بمقدور الآخرين ارتكاب الجريمة آنذاك أيضاً؟
Besides, it was by sheer chance that Kiwako-san started to drown.
كما أنّ اندفاعهم لنجدتها حصل صدفةً بعدما غرقت
And what if it wasn't by chance?
وماذا إذا لم يكن ذلك صدفة؟
What if Kiwako-san had done it on purpose?
ماذا لو غرقت كيواكو-سان عمداً؟
On purpose? What for?
عمداً؟ لمَ؟
It's natural for lovers to want to know the other's true feelings.
من الطبيعيّ للرجال والنساء أن يريدوا معرفة ما بأعماق البعض
To arouse the other's interest, one might get close to another person,
لإثارة الطرف الآخر، قد تتعمّد للتقرّب من شخص آخر
or even purposely not wear a wedding ring...
أو تتعمّد نزع خاتم زواجك
Then, you're saying Kiwako-san...
...أتقصد أنّ كيواكو-سان
Yes.
أجل
Kiwako-san pretended to drown to test Masahiko-san, her fiancé.
تظاهرت كيواكو-سان بالغرق كي تختبر خطيبها ماساهيكو-سان
To see if he would come to her rescue, even though he can't swim.
لترى إذا ما سيهبّ من لا يجيد السباحة لنجدتها
As proof, she murmured this after confirming that he tried to help...
ودليلاً على ذلك، تمتمت كيواكو-سان بما يلي بعدما تأكّدت
"That's a relief..."
"حمداً لله"
But they're getting married next week. Why do that now?
لكنّهما سيتزوّجان الأسبوع القادم، فلمَ تفعل ذلك الآن؟
She wanted to be extra sure.
أرادت أن تتأكّد أكثر
She was irritated that her fiancé didn't even bat an eye
كانت ممتعضةً من خطيبها الذي لم يبادر لتوبيخها
when she clung to this famous celebrity.
رغم انفتانها بهذا الشخص المشهور
And then she executed the fake drowning plan they made in advance.
وأقدمت على خطّة التظاهر بالغرق التي اتّفقتا عليها سلفاً
"They"?
ماذا؟ اتّفقتا؟
Yes. Two people.
أجل، الاثنتان
For the plan to work, someone had to tell Masahiko-san right away.
لتنجح هذه الخطّة، يجب أن يكون هناك من يخبر ماساهيكو-سان بغرقها فوراً
It'd be a disgrace if someone else on the beach rescued her first.
سيكون من المعيب لو أنقذها أحد آخر على الشاطئ قبل أن ينتبه هو
And that other person was you, Harumi-san.
وذاك الشخص الآخر كان أنت يا هارومي-سان
The signal for the start of the plan was probably when she said...
:إشارة بدء الخطّة كانت قولها لك
Could you get a fresh beach towel from our room?
أيمكنك جلب منشفة استحمام جديدة من غرفتنا؟
Or so I'd assume. After that...
...وفقما أظنّ، وبعدها
Later, Harumi! Don't forget!
!إلى اللقاء يا هارومي! أعتمد عليك
...Is something else she said, so that sounds about right.
،قالت كيواكو-سان ذلك هذا ما حصل غالباً
But Harumi-san tried to stop her from going into the water!
لكن حاولت هارومي-سان منعها من دخول البحر آنذاك
Besides, she wouldn't have done that in front of a famous detective!
كما كيف تقدم على ذلك أمام متحرٍّ شهير؟
That's why she tried to stop her. Because I was right there watching.
لذا حاولتْ منعها، فقد كنتُ أشاهد
You don't have to do it today. Can't you go tomorrow?
ليس عليكِ فعلها اليوم، ألا تؤجلينها للغد؟
I'll be fine!
!سأكون بخير
But Kiwako-san continued with the plan anyway.
لكن مضت كيواكو-سان بالخطّة دون مراعاة
Unaware that Harumi-san had another, more sinister plan in store.
في جهلها أنّ هيرومي-سان كانت تحيك خطّة شرّيرة أخرى
Y-You can't be serious...
...لا-لا يمكن
Upon returning to her room to get the bath towel,
،بعد عودتها للغرفة لجلب منشفة الاستحمام
Harumi-san concealed her sea snake in her pouch
وضعت أفعى البحر التي كانت تخبّئها في حقيبة خصرها
and went back to the seaside restaurant.
ورجعت للمطعم الشاطئيّ
Then, at the proper time, she signaled Kiwako-san to falsely drown.
ثمّ، أرسلت الإشارة لـ كيواكو-سان بعدما ترقّبت الوقت المناسب لتتظاهر بالغرق
Then, when rushing to help with everyone else,
وعندما هرعت إليها مع البقيّة
she took out the hidden sea snake and had it bite Kiwako-san.
أخرجت أفعى البحر التي كانت تخفيها وجعلتها تعضّ كيواكو-سان
But what's your plan, Great Detective?
لكن ما الذي تنوي فعله يا حضرة المتحرّي؟
The murder weapon is gracefully swimming in the Pacific Ocean.
فلا بدّ أنّ سلاح الجريمة يسبح بحريّة في المحيط الهادئ الآن
Without a weapon, this case won't stand up in court.
باختفاء السلاح، فلن تثبت التهمة في المحاكمة
I already told you. She placed the sea snake in her waist pouch.
أخبرتكم، وضعت أفعى البحر في حقيبة خصرها
What's more, whether out of confidence or confusion,
،كما، سواءً كان الدافع هو الثقة، أم الارتباك
she never left our side after the incident.
فهي لم تفارقنا منذ الحادثة
It should still be there in her pouch:
لا بدّ أنّه سيكون موجوداً في حقيبة خصرها
adhesive tape with black-banded sea krait scales still attached!
الشريط اللاصق بحراشف أفعى البحر المخطّطة السوداء السامة
Tape?
الشريط؟
Yes.
أجل
Simply stuffing it in would make it seem unnatural when taking it out,
مجرّد إقحام الأفعى سيجعل إخراجها يستغرق وقتاً، وأمراً ملفتاً للأنظار
and there'd be a chance it could bite her fingers instead.
وهناك احتمال عضّها لأصابعها إذا لم تتوخّ الحذر
She most likely taped the snake down in several spots in the pouch
فقامت بلصق أفعى البحر في عدّة مواضع في حقيبة خصرها غالباً
and left only the snake's head sticking out.
وتركت رأسها فحسب بارزاً للخارج
That way, she could pull it out and have it bite in an instant.
هكذا يمكنها الإمساك به وجعلها تعضّ فورياً
Then the wing-like things I saw on the snake were...
إذاً... الشيء الشبيه بالأجنحة ...الذي رأيتُه على أفعى البحر
Probably some of the tape.
كان جزءاً من الشريط غالباً
The rest of the tape is probably still inside her pouch.
وبقيّة الشريط لا تزال في حقيبة خصرها على الأرجح
Inside her pouch?
في حقيبتها؟
But we still don't know for sure she put a snake in--
لكن لا نستطيع الجزم بعد ...بأنّها أدخلت الأفعى في حقيبة
We do. Because of her card key.
بل نستطيع، بسبب بطاقة مفتاحها
As soon as I saw her compact, wallet, and everything
عندما رأيتُ علبة تجميلها ومحفظتها
on top of the card key she left in the room, it hit me
فوق بطاقة المفتاح التي تركتها في الغرفة، أدركتُ شيئاً
that she might've emptied her pouch and put something else in it.
لعلّها فرّغت حقيبتها، ووضعت شيئاً آخر بالداخل
But why would she harm Kiwako-san?! She's her brother's fiancée!
لكن لمَ قد تقدم على أذيّة كيواكو-سان؟ إنّها خطيبة أخيها، فلمَ؟
This is purely speculation,
...هذا مجرّد تخمين
but I wonder if Harumi-san might've liked Masahiko-san.
لكن أتساءل لو كانت هارومي-سان معجبةً بـ ماساهيكو-سان؟
No... loved him. A lot.
كلا... بل أكثر من ذلك، واقعة في حبّه
Don't be silly, Dad! She and Masahiko-san are brother and sister!
ما الذي تقوله يا أبي؟! هارومي-سان !وماساهيكو-سان شقيقان
No. They probably aren't.
كلا، ليسا كذلك على الأرجح
If they were, all four in their group would've been childhood friends.
لو كان الأمر صحيحاً، فيُفترض أنّ مجموعة أصدقاء الطفولة كانت من 4 أفراد
Especially given that she's the same age as Kiwako-san.
وخصوصاً أنّها بنفس سنّ كيواكو-سان
Then they're step-siblings from when their parents remarried?
أي أيمكن أنّهما أخوان غير شقيقين من زواج والديهما الثاني؟
Yes. Probably.
نعم، غالباً
Seeing as Hiroshi-san calls her "-san" even though she's younger,
من إضافة هيروشي-سان لـ "سان" عند مناداتها رغم أنّها تصغره سنّاً
they were probably in college when it happened.
فالأمر حصل عندما كانا في الجامعة على الأرجح
No. It was my second year in high school
ليس في الجامعة، بل سنتي الثانية في الثانويّة
when my mom remarried and I first met Masahiko-san.
تزوّجت أمّي ثانيةً، والتقيتُ ماساهيكو-سان وقتها لأوّل مرّة
He's a little helpless but nice, and I fell for him.
ليس أهلاً للمسؤولية نوعاً ما، لكنّه كان لطيفاً جدّاً، وانجذبت له تدريجياً
I never had anyone like him around me before.
فلم يكن هناك أشخاص مثله حولي
But Kiwako-san was always by his side.
لكن كانت كيواكو-سان بجواره دوماً
Whenever she spoke about his childhood, I'd get very sad and angry.
كلّما تكلّمتْ عن طفولته، شعرت بالحزن والغيض
It was like she was saying, "You don't know anything about him!"
"بدت كأنّها تقول: "أنتِ لا تعرفين شيئاً عنه
My only choice was to hide my feelings and call him my brother.
كان خياري الوحيد إخفاء مشاعري ومناداته بأخي
Their sudden engagement and marriage was a huge shock.
كانت خطبتهما المفاجئة وزواجهما صدمةً كبيرة
To top it all off, she came to me with that plan, knowing how I felt.
وفوق ذلك، اقترحت تلك الفكرة لي وهي تعرف مشاعري
Almost as if she was mocking me.
كما لو كانت تسخر منّي
Pretending to drown?
تتظاهرين بالغرق؟
Please? Can you do it?
من فضلك، ساعديني
And then you devised your own plan?
ثمّ فكّرتِ بخطّة أفعى البحر؟
Yes. That's right.
أجل، صحيح
I didn't want to hand Masahiko-san over to her! So I...
...لم أرد أن أسلّم ماساهيكو-سان لها! لذا
So I...
...لذا
I'm so stupid, aren't I? Doing that would only make him sad...
.يا لحماقتي، إنّه حُب من طرف واحد فعل ذلك سيُحزن ماساهيكو-سان لا أكثر
I'm really so stupid...
أنا حمقاء بالفعل
You're Toda Kiwako-san's friends, correct?!
أنتم أصدقاء تودا كيواكو-سان، صحيح؟
We managed to administer an antitoxin just in time!
!تمكّنا من إعطائها الترياق في الوقت
A few more days and she'll be just fine!
ستكون بخيرٍ بعد تنويمها هنا لبضعة أيام
It's all thanks to your emergency treatment!
هذا بفضل إسعافكم الطارئ
It was nothing!
لم يكن شيئاً
That's wonderful news, Kiwako!
أليس هذا رائعاً يا كيواكو؟
W-Where's Harumi?
أ-أين هارومي؟
She's here! Harumi!
!إنّها هنا، هارومي
C'mon! Why so bashful?
هيّا، لمَ الخجل؟
I'm sorry.
آسفة
I didn't know how you felt...
لم أعرف مشاعرك
I had no idea, until I saw your serious look when you rushed to me.
لم تكن لديّ أيّ فكرة حتّى رأيت ملامحك الجادة عندما هرعتِ لي
Kiwako...
...كيواكو
Yet, I asked you for that favor... I'm really sorry! I regret it!
...مع ذلك، طلبتُ منكِ ذلك أنا آسفة حقّاً، أنا نادمة
What are you saying?! I tried to... I tried to...
...ما الذي تقولينه؟! كنتُ من
W-Wait! Did something happen?!
ما-ما الأمر؟ أحصل شيءٌ ما؟
It's nothing. I was punished for testing the heart of another.
لا شيء
That's why a sea snake bit me.
لذا عضّتني أفعى البحر
That's all.
ذلك ما بالأمر
That was amazing detective work again, Dad!
كان استنتاجك مذهلاً كالعادة يا أبي
Sometimes I can't remember anything at all...
لا أتذكّر شيئاً منه البتّة أحياناً
Plus, it sounds like you noticed what Mom did.
كما يبدو أنّك لاحظت ما قامت به أمّي
Oh? Noticing but pretending not to know is all the worse.
!ماذا؟ لاحظت، لكنّك تظاهرت بالجهل هذا يزيد الطين بلّة
Mom!
!أمّي
What's she talking about?
ما الذي تتكلّم عنه؟
Look at you playing dumb again!
!تتظاهر بالحماقة مُجدداً
She's talking about the ring!
!تقصد الخاتم
Ring?
الخاتم؟
You mean this?
تقصدين هذا؟
No way!
محال
I found it under the beach umbrella you were using.
وجدته أسفل مظلّة الشاطئ التي كنتِ تجلسين تحتها
How did you know I lost my ring there?!
كيف عرفت أنّي فقدت خاتمي هناك؟
Don't be stupid. Nobody dries their hair with their glasses on.
حمقاء، لا يجفّف أحد شعره وهو يرتدي نظّارات
That was evidence you were looking for something.
كان ذلك برهاناً على بحثك عن شيء
People really only lose contacts, earrings, and rings on beaches.
ما يفقده الناس على الشاطئ هو العدسات اللاصقة وأقراط الأذن والخواتم وما شابه
So the sand on your knees was because you were looking for the ring!
الرمل على ركبتيك كان لأنّك تبحث عن الخاتم إذاً؟
I get it! You wanted to tell her about the ring!
فهمت، ما أردت الكلام عنه معها كان الخاتم
The old guy did notice!
لاحظ العمّ بالفعل إذاً
Geez. If only he was always that sharp.
يا إلهي، ليت حدّة ذهنه هذه تلازمه
Besides, could you be any more obvious?
كما جعلتِ الأمر جليّاً جدّاً
Drinking tea with your left hand, wringing your hands nervously...
،تتعمّدين شرب الشاي بيدك اليسرى تهزّين يدك بتوتر
I couldn't help it...
...لكن
Mori Kogoro-san!
!إنّه موري كوغورو-سان
Hi!
!أجل
Dad! Hey, Dad!
!أبي! لحظة، أبي
Mom!
!أمّي
Alright! Next time for sure!
!حسنٌ، المرة القادمة حتماً
It'll never, ever happen.
مستحيل، لن تنجحي أبداً
They match perfectly!
إنّهما متطابقان
I wonder why the ones in chapters one through six are all slightly off.
توقيع الفصول من الأوّل حتّى السادس مختلف قليلاً، فلمَ يا ترى؟
He obviously copied an earlier signature.
من الجليّ أنّه نسخ توقيعاً سابقاً
Why would he do that?
ولمَ قد يفعل ذلك؟
Because he didn't want to write it anymore...
...لأنّه لم يعد يريد الكتابة
...or he couldn't anymore?
أو لم يعد يستطيع؟
That means Shinmei-sensei might already be dead, doesn't it?
ألا يعني ذلك أنّ شينمي سينسي قد يكون ميتاً بالفعل؟
On the next Conan--
الحلقة القادمة من كونان
"The Mystery Writer Disappearance Case (Part 1)."
جريمة اختفاء روائيّ الغموض (الجزء الأوّل)
Next Conan's hint:
تلميح الحلقة القادمة
One half.
نصفان في القمّة
Next episode is a mystery about a mystery writer.
الحلقة القادمة غامضةٌ !عن روائيّ غموض
The most mysterious thing of all is the mystery.
!أكبر غموض هو غموض
That's right.
وما تقول